Guide to the Archives of Irish America Vertical Files AIA.013
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Archives of Irish America Vertical Files
1841-2025
1970-2009
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Archives of Irish America
AIA.013
45.19 Linear Feet in 21 record cartons, 26 manuscript boxes, 3 half manuscript boxes, 2 flat boxes, 6 oversize flat boxes, 1 CD box, 1 media box, 1 folder in shared housing, and 1 flat file folder
988 Megabytes in 105 files
38 VHS
37 Betacam_SP
1 audiocassette
1 DAT
25 MiniDV
9 DVCAM
3 film reels
The Vertical Files collection was created via active collection by staff, contributions from donors, and from material removed from collections in the Archives. Materials collected on individuals, organizations, and topics related to various aspects of Irish American history, culture, and social life are included in the collection. The collection includes contracts, constitutions, flyers, broadsides, leaflets, clippings, reports, pamphlets, catalogs, brochures, bibliographies, press releases, programs, posters, sheet music, audiovisual materials, some born-digital materials, and other printed ephemera.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The vertical files collection was created via active collection by staff, contributions from donors and from material removed from collections in the Archives. Accretions to the collection were donated by Marion Casey in July 2018, August 2019, March 2025, and December 2025. Another accretion to the collection was donated by Loretta Brennan in July 2018. The accession numbers associated with this collection are 1997.020, 2018.092, 2018.121, 2019.113, 2025.032, and 2026.010.
Arrangement
The collection is organized alphabetically by name, title, or topic. Oversize materials are also organized alphabetically in a separate series at the end of the collection.
Historical Note
The Vertical Files collection contains information on various topics, events, and individuals affiliated with the Archives of Irish America (AIA). The materials in this collection -- such as flyers, posters, and pamphlets -- provide insight to scholars and researchers regarding methods used to convey information within the Irish-American community.
Scope and Contents
The Vertical Files collection is an artificial collection of materials on various topics, individuals, and organizations, both Irish-American and Irish. The collection includes contracts, constitutions, flyers, broadsides, leaflets, clippings, reports, pamphlets, catalogs, brochures, bibliographies, press releases, programs, posters, sheet music, audiovisual materials, some born-digital materials, and other printed ephemera.
The bulk of this collection represents the type of literature that has commonly circulated within the New York Irish community since 1970. Information on more than 100 non-profit Irish American political and cultural organizations and events, businesses, the Irish language, one-time events such as demonstrations and poetry readings, and individuals is included. Also included are clippings and articles on famous Irish-Americans, gift catalogs, and information relating to publications. Some of the more documented institutions and topics covered are the Emerald Isle Immigration Center, the Glucksman Ireland House, the Irish American Cultural Institute, Irish Books and Media, Inc., The Irish Repertory Theatre, Saint Patrick's Day Parade organizations and events, and theater productions on and off Broadway. The majority of materials date from the 1970s and on.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Born-Digital Access Policies and Procedures
An access terminal for born-digital materials in the collection is available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Researchers may view an item's original container and/or carrier, but the physical carriers themselves are not available for use because of preservation concerns. Advance notice is required for the use of computer records. Original physical digital media is restricted.
Publications (documents); Fliers (printed matter); Theater programs.; Pamphlets.; Irish Americans -- Politics and government.; Theatre.; Irish Americans -- New York (N.Y.) -- Social life and customs.; Hunger strikes -- Northern Ireland.; Immigrants -- United States.; Ireland -- History -- Easter Rising, 1916; Irish Americans.; Playbills.; Immigrants -- United States -- History -- 20th century.; Political prisoners -- Ireland.; Publishers and publishing -- United States.; Labor unions; Immigrants -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Irish Americans -- Music.; Saint Patrick's Day.; Irish Americans -- Societies, etc.; Irish Americans -- Social life and customs.; Fundraising.; Flannery, Michael, 1902-1994; O'Neill, Tip; Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963; Knights of Columbus; De Valera, Eamon, 1882-1975; Irish American Cultural Institute; Claidheamh Soluis (New York, N.Y.); Irish American Building Society; Clan-na-Gael; Emerald Isle Immigration Center; Catholic Church--United States; Friendly Sons of St. Patrick; U2 (Musical group); Glucksman Ireland House; O'Hara, Maureen, 1920-2015; Columbia University; Boston College; American Conference for Irish Studies; American Ireland Fund; American-Irish Historical Society
- #
  - 1st Annual New York Trad Fest, 2013 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - The 9th Annual Philadelphia Rose of Tralee Selection Night Gala, 2010 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - 15th Annual Catskills Irish Arts Week, 2009 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - 26th Annual St. Patrick's Day Parade and Festival, 2006 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - 92nd Biennial Convention (AOH), 2004 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - 96th Anniversary 1916 Rising, 2012 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - 97th Anniversary 1916 Easter Rising, 2013 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - 98th Anniversary 1916 Easter Rising, 2014 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - 175 Years of Fidelity to God and Country: A History of the Ancient Order of Hibernians in America, 2011 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - 215th Anniversary Dinner of the Society of the Friendly Sons of St. Patrick, 1999 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - 228th Saint Patrick's Day Parade, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - 230th Saint Patrick's Day Parade, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - 231st St. Patrick's Day Parade, 1992 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - The 1757 Bordeaux Dublin Letters Conference, 2013 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - 1916 Easter Uprising & Hunger Strike Memorial Mass and Commemorative Ceremony, 2011 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - 1916 Societies News, undated (Box 26, Folder 16)
- A
  - Abraham Lincoln & the American Irish, 2012 (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Abu-Jamal, Mumia, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Address Book, undated (Box 42, Folder 22)
  - The Adrian Flannelly Show, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Advertisements, 1998 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Aer Lingus, 1979 (Box 1)
  - After the Celtic Tiger: Picking Up the Pieces" with Frank McDonald, 2011 (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Aireagal, 2002-2004 (Box 1)
  - Aisling Irish Community Center, 2005-2006 (Box 1, Box 54, Folder 1)
  - All-Ireland Camogie, 1990 (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - All Ireland Football Final Banquet, 1947 (Box 42, Folder 23)
  - Allied Irish Banks, 1975-1998 (Box 1)
  - The Ambassadorship of Literature (Glucksman Ireland House), 2013 (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - American Bicentennial, 1974-1976 (Box 1)
  - The American Civil War and the Irish, 1998 (Box 1)
  - American Commission on Irish Independence, undated (Box 1)
  - The American Committee for Relief in Ireland (An Cumann Cabhrach), 1921 (Box 1)
  - American Committee for Sean O'Casey's Centenary, 1979 (Box 1)
  - American Committee for Ulster Justice, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - American Committee for Ulster Justice: Newsletters, 1972-1973 (Box 26, Folder 22)
  - American Conference for Irish Studies, 1963-2015 (Box 1, Box 34, Folder 3)
  - American Foundation for Irish Heritage, 1990-1993 (Box 1)
  - American Friends of James Joyce, 1998-2005 (Box 1, Box 34, Folder 4)
  - The American Friends of the Linen Hall Library Belfast, undated (Box 26, Folder 23)
  - The American Ireland Fund - 38th Annual New York Dinner Gala, 2013 (Box 26, Folder 24)
  - The American Ireland Fund: Connections [4 folders], 1994-2001 (Box 1, Box 37)
  - The American Ireland Fund: Dinner Dances, 1995-2013 (Box 1, Box 34, Folder 5, Box 37)
  - American Irish Association Handbook, circa 1940 (Box 1)
  - American-Irish Association of Westchester County, 1977, 1986-1988, 1994 (Box 2)
  - American Irish Celtic USA Stamp Committee, 1998-1999 (Box 2)
  - American Irish Cultural Project, 1979 (Box 2)
  - American Irish Defense Association, circa 1942 (Box 2)
  - American Irish Foundation, 1976 (Box 2)
  - American-Irish Historical Society, 1981-2006, 2014 (Box 2, Box 34, Folder 6, Box 26, Folder 25)
  - American Irish Immigration Center, 1968 (Box 2)
  - American Irish Library, undated (Box 2)
  - American Irish Musicians Society, 1985 (Box 2)
  - American Irish National Immigration Committee, 1969 (Box 2)
  - The American Irish Newsletter [1 legal-size folder, 1 oversize folder], 1984, 1987 (Box 20)
  - American Irish Society of the Rockaways, 1974 (Box 38)
  - The American Irish Society of Westchester County, 1992 (Box 2)
  - American Irish Teachers Association, Inc., 2009-2015 (Box 2, Box 34, Folder 7, Box 26, Folder 26)
  - American Irish Unity Committee, 1981 (Box 2, Box 26, Folder 27)
  - American League for an Undivided Ireland, undated (Box 2)
  - An Claidheamh Soluis, 2006 (Box 2)
  - An Club Leabhar, 1996-1997 (Box 2)
  - An Comunn Gaidhealach Ameireaga, 1996 (Box 2)
  - An Féinics, 1969 (Box 2)
  - An Gaeilgeoir, 2002 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - An Gorta Mór, 2000 (Box 2)
  - An Scáthán (The Celtic Mirror), 1997 (Box 2)
  - An Scoil Chois Clai (The Hedge School), 2010 (Box 26, Folder 28)
  - An Scoil Ghaeilge (The Irish School), circa 1980-1996 (Box 2)
  - An Scoil Nua, 1993-1996 (Box 2)
  - An Teanga Mharthanach, 1990-1996 (Box 2)
  - Anamchairde Network, Inc., 1995-1999 (Box 2)
  - Ancient Order of Hibernians, 1974-2013 (Box 2, Box 34, Folder 8, Box 26, Folder 29)
  - Ancient Order of Hibernians: District of Columbia State Board, 2007 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Ancient Order of Hibernians District of Columbia State Board State Convention & Banquet, 2011 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Ancient Order of Hibernians in America - National Board, 2005 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Ancient Order of Hibernians in America - National President's Dinner, 2003 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Ancient Order of Hibernians Ladies Auxiliary, New York State Convention, 1939 (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Anti-Apartheid Movement, circa 1990 (Box 2)
  - Anti Internment Coalition (New York), 1972 (Box Shared Tamiment 183, Folder 13)
  - Annotated Catalogue and Bibliography for the Column Collection of the Library at State University of New York at Binghamton, 1970 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Annual Easter Mass & 1916 Commemoration, 2012 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - AOH 91st Biennial Convention, 2006 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - AOH 92nd Biennial Convention, 2004 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - AOH Division 5, Woodlawn Pre-St. Patrick's Day Party, undated (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - AOH/LAOH National Convention, 2010 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - AOH/LAOH National Convention 93rd Biennial Convention Boston, 2006 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - AOH/LAOH 94th Biennial Convention - New Orleans, 2008 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - AOH Michael L. Delahunty Division No. Nine 112th Anniversary Dinner Dance, 2012 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - AOH Nassau County Feis & Festival - 38th Annual Feis, 2010 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Archives of Irish America, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Aristocrats (Playbill Program), 1989 (Box 42, Folder 24)
  - Armstrong, Michael Joseph, 2001 (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Art Exhibitions [1 legal-size folder, 1 oversize folder], 1973-2008 (Box 2, Oversize 22)
  - Art Auction Catalogs, 1999-2001 (Box 2)
  - Art From the Edge: New Irish Art, 1995-1996 (Box 2)
  - Artane Boys Band at Gaelic Park, 1961 (Box 2)
  - Ashe, Thomas, 2001 (Box 21)
  - Associated Irish Societies of New York, 1963, 1980 (Box 2)
  - Association to Promote Intercultural Relations, 1994 (Box 2)
  - Atlas of the Great Irish Famine, undated (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Authors, 1997-1999 (Box 2)
- B
  - Bailis, Moira, 1990-1995 (Box 2)
  - Bank of Ireland, 1987-1993 (Box 2)
  - Basilica of St. Patrick's Old Cathedral, 2009, 2015 (Box 27, Folder 17, Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Behan, Mae, 1947-1948, 1994 (Box 2, Box 54, Folder 23)
  - Benefit Dances, 1993, 2004 (Box 2)
  - Bergen Irish Association, 1989 (Box 2)
  - The Bernard Shaw Society, 1986, 1994-1999 (Box 2)
  - Bewley's of Ireland, 1994-2000 (Box 2)
  - Bibliographies (includes bibliography on Irish Women), 1995, undated (Box 2)
  - Big Apple Politics and Catholic New York 1845-1945, undated (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - The Many Stories of Billy the Kid, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Biographies from Radical History, undated (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Blarney Woolen Mills Gift Catalogue, 1997-2002 (Box 20)
  - Bloomsday: Celebration of James Joyce, 1991-2004 (Box 2)
  - Bonded Shores, 1997-2000 (Box 2)
    Former Title
    Bonded Shores was formerly called the Carolina Irish
  - Book Announcement from U.S. Publishers, 1998 (Box 3)
  - Book Events, 1965-2001, undated (Box 3)
  - Book Reviews, 1989-2001, undated (Box 3)
  - Book Sellers, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Books Written in Irish, 1998 (Box 3)
  - Boston College, 1993-2017 (Box 3, Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Boston College - Center for Irish Programs, 2000-2012 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Boston College Gaelic Roots Festival, 1997 (Box 3)
  - Boston College: Irish Film Series, undated (Box 3, Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Boston Irish Tourism Association, undated (Box 3)
  - Brady, Fr. Coman V., 2010 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Brehon Law Society, 1994, 2006-2009 (Box 3, Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Breslin, Jimmy, 1986 (Box 3)
  - Broadway [Theater for Broadway, Off-Broadway, and Off-Off-Broadway Productions]
  - Brooklyn Academy of Music, 1937 (Box 3)
  - Brooklyn Irish American Parade Committee, Inc., 1992 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Brooklyn Irish American Parade Committee, Inc., 2012 (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Brooklyn Public Library: Irish Language Classes, circa 1996 (Box 3)
  - Brooklyn St. Patrick's Day Parade, 2011 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Buckley, Charles A. (politician), undated (Box 20)
  - Bucks County Irish Center, 1995 (Box 3)
  - Bulger, James "Whitey", 2001 (Box 3)
  - The Bulletin photograph, undated (Box 42, Folder 25)
  - Burke, Michael, 1987 (Box 3)
  - Business Cards, undated (Box 3)
  - Business Directories, 1991-2000 (Box 3)
  - Businesses Based in Ireland and England, 1994-1995 (Box 3)
  - Businesses Based in NYC, 1995 (Box 3)
  - Businesses Based in the U.S., 1990 (Box 3)
  - Butler, Father Francis, 1997-1998 (Box 3)
  - Byrne, John, 1978 (Box 3)
- C
  - Caldwell, Marc, 1999 (Box 3)
  - Campbell, Father Colm, 2000, 2010 (Box 3, Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Carmel Quinn's Irish Festival of Stars (Carnegie Hall Programs), 1965 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Carmelite Parishes, 1988-1989 (Box 3)
  - Carmelites: Centennial, 1989 (Box 3)
  - Carroll, Michael T. (Firefighter), 2001 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - The Casey Family, 2001 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Cashs of Ireland [2 folders], 1997-2002 (Box 3)
  - Cathedral of St. Patrick - New York City, 2001 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Catholic Churches and Events, 1945-2009 (Box 3)
  - Catholic Ireland - Past, Present, Future (Fordham Center on Religion and Culture), 2013 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Catholic Schools, 1948-2009 (Box 3)
  - Catholic University of America: Irish Studies, 1993-1998 (Box 3)
  - Catskills Irish Arts Week, 1994-2013 (Box 3, Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Cee Vee Productions, 1998 (Box 3)
  - Celebrating 250 Years of the New York City Saint Patrick's Day Parade. John Ridge and Lynn Mosher Bushnell. Quinnipiac University Press. 2010. Publicity and promotional materials. (Box 3)
  - Celebrating Irish Heritage - First Annual Irish Photo Exhibit and Competition, undated (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Ceili and Two-Handed Dance, 2011 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Celtic Appalachia (Irish Arts Center), undated (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Celtic League American Branch, 1974-1999, 2005 (Box 3)
  - Celtic Studies Association, 1992-1996 (Box 3)
  - The Celtic Tenors, 2013 (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Celtic Video/Celtic Productions, circa 1988-1995 (Box 3)
  - Ceol Na Ngael, 1991 (Box 5)
  - The Charitable Irish Society, 1987 (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Charities: Ethnic Appeals, 1991-2000 (Box 5)
  - Charities: Religious, circa 1989-1999 (Box 5)
  - Charity for Families and Individuals in Need, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Checks from American Irish Film Institute, 1952 (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Cherish the Ladies photograph, undated (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Chicago Irish American News, Dec 1979 (Box 20)
  - Chicago Irish Folklife Society, 1979-1980, 1987 (Box 5, Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Childhood and Ireland - An Interdisciplinary Lecture Series, undated (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Church of Saint Francis Xavier, 1989 (Box 5)
  - The Church of Saint James, 1995 (Box 5)
  - Church of Saint Teresa, 1996 (Box 5)
  - Cineaste, 1999 (Box 5)
  - Citizenship and Nationalism (Irish), 1971, 1996, undated (Box 5)
  - The City Center, circa 1950 (Box 5)
  - City of New York Guide for Irish Immigrants, 1974-1989 (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - City University of New York, 1993-2002 (Box 5)
  - City University of New York Institute for Irish Studies, 1992-2016 (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - Civil War Soldiers, 1992 (Box 5)
  - Clan Associations and Societies in the U.S., 1992 (Box 5)
  - Clan na Gael, 1951-2000 (Box 5, Box 34, Folder 17, Box 38)
  - Clan Na Gael and Irish Republican Army Veterans of America, 1952-1956 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Co. Corksmens B.P. & P. Ass., undated (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Collins, Ray, circa 1986 (Box 5)
  - Colonel Thomas J. Kelly of the Fenian Brotherhood, undated (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - Columban Fathers [1 legal-size folder, 1 oversize folder], 1971-1976 (Box 4)
  - Columbia University: Irish Studies, 1970-2000 (Box 5, Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Comhairle Na Gcumann Gaeilge, 1967 (Box 5)
  - Comhaltas Ceoltóirí Éireann [2 folders], 1972-2000 (Box 5, Box 28, Folder 21)
  - Comhaltas Ceoltóirí Éireann, 2008 (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Commemorating Ireland's Participation in the World's Fair New York, 1939 (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - Commemorating the Centenary of the 1913 Dublin Lockout (The County Cork B.P. & P. Association), 2013 (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - Commodore Barry Club of Brooklyn, 1976 (Box 5)
  - Concerts, 1945 (Box 5)
  - Conferences, 2005 (Box 22)
  - Congressman Mario Biaggi 90th Birthday Celebration, 2007 (Box 28, Folder 22)
  - Connacht GAA Football, 2009 (Box 28, Folder 23)
  - Connect Magazine: The American Ireland Fund, 2008-2013 (Box 28, Folder 24)
  - Connecticut Irish-American Historical Society, 1990-2001 (Box 5)
  - Connor, Jerome (1874-1943): Irish-American sculptor, 1993 (Box 20)
  - Conradh Na Gaeilge: New York, 1998 (Box 5)
  - Conradh Na Gaeilge: Texas, 1993-1994 (Box 5)
  - Conradh Na Gaeilge: Washington, 1990-1999 (Box 5)
  - Conradh Na Gaeilge: Wisconsin, 1995 (Box 5)
  - Constitution of Ireland, 1980 (Box 5)
  - Consulate Genearl of Ireland, 2012 (Box 28, Folder 25)
  - Consulate General of Ireland in New York, 1999-2016 (Box 22, Box 5, Box 34, Folder 18, Flat-file-folder 5)
  - Consultants, 1996-2009 (Box 5)
  - Convocation - Dublin City University, 2013 (Box 28, Folder 26)
  - Conway, Michael- "Justice for Michael Conway" Issued by the Conway Defence Picket Line Committee), 1936 (Box 5)
  - Cooke, Terence J., 1968, 1981, 1983, 2011 (Box 5, Box 28, Folder 27)
  - Cooking, 1987-2009 (Box 5)
  - Co-Operation Ireland, 1992 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence - Charles G. Maloney (Auxiliary Bishop), 1957 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence in Gaelic, 1996 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence - George J. Barrett, 1949 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence - Thomas McElroy, 1987 (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence - Irish Northern Aid Committee, 1975 (Box 28, Folder 28)
  - Cork University Press, 1997-2001 (Box 5)
  - Count me, I'm Irish!" United States Census 2010 (Box 28, Folder 29)
  - County Armagh Association of New York Inc., 2011 (Box 28, Folder 30)
  - County Armagh Association of New York, Inc Armagh Gaelic Football Club of New York, 2011 (Box 28, Folder 31)
  - County Clare Patriotic Benevolent & Social Association of New York City, Inc. 120th Annual Ball, 2008 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - County Cork Association of New York, 2012 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - The County Cork B.P. & P. Association of New York 125th Anniversary Banquet, 2009 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - The County Cork B.P. & P. Association of New York 126th Annual St. Patrick's Day Dinner Dance, 2010 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - County Longford Social Club, 1999 (Box 51, Vhs 013.0004)
  - Craic Fest, 2015 (Box 34, Folder 19)
  - Creative Irish Gifts [3 folders], 1997-2005 (Box 20)
  - Crests and Coat of Arms; Family Names, 1901-1962 (Box 5)
  - Croí West of Ireland Cardiology Foundation, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Cronin, Sean, undated (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Bing Crosby Sheet Music, 1944, 1947 (Box 5)
  - Crossroads Irish American Festival, 2004 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Croton Aqueduct Department Papers, 1851, 1857 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Cruises: Irish-Themed, 1992 (Box 5)
  - Cuala NYC, 2016 (Box 34, Folder 20)
  - Cudahy, Dorothy Hayden, 1951-2009 (Box 5)
  - Cuimachuain - 1916 Easter Rebellion, 2011 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Cuite, Thomas J., 2000 (Box 20)
  - Cultural Arts, 1997-2000 (Box 6)
  - Culture Ireland - Promoting Irish Arts Worldwide, 2013 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Cumann Breandain, 1992-1997 (Box 6)
  - Cumann Luthchleas Gael, 1996-1999 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Cumann Na Gaeilge, 1999 (Box 6)
  - Cumann na Saoirse Naisiunta (2012 Easter Commemoration) (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Curley, James Michael, 1992 (Box 6)
  - Curran, Sean, 1999-2000 (Box 6)
- D
  - Daltaí Na Gaeilge, 2003-2009 (Box 6)
  - Dance, 1969-2000 (Box 6)
  - Dance Study Programs, 1999, undated (Box 6)
  - Dancing on Dangerous Ground, 2000 (Box 20)
  - Dancing at Lughnasa (Playbill Program), 1991 (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - The Daniel Patrick Moynihan Lecture (Glucksman Ireland House), undated (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Dara Records Irish Music News and Catalog, 1998-2009 (Box 6)
  - De Valera Address to Joint Houses of Congress, 1964 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - De Valera, Eamonn, 1945-2009 (Box 6, Box 54, Folder 14)
  - Defence Forces 2008 GAA Tour (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Diary Entry about Hunger Strike, 1982 (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Doherty, Joe, circa 1984 (Box 6)
  - Dolan, Felix Joseph, undated (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - The Douglas Hyde Foundation for Irish-Medium Education, 1991-1994 (Box 6)
  - Down These Green Streets: Irish Crime Writing in the 21st Century (Declan Burke), 2011 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Clare Droesch, 2000 (Box 6)
  - Dufour Editions, Inc. [3 folders], 1994-1997 (Box 6)
  - Durkan, Frank, 2000-2006, 2012 (Box 6, Box 22, Box 29, Folder 16)
- E
  - Eagle Tavern and the Blarney Star, 1991-2001 (Box 6)
  - Easter - Tree of Liberty, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - Easter Uprising Commemoration, 1969-1995 (Box 20)
  - Easter Uprising of 1916 [2 folders], 1961-1997 (Box 6)
  - Echoes by Michael Hannon, undated (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - Echoes of Erin Association, 25th Anniversary, 1962 (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Echoes of Irish History, by Mike McCormack, undated (Box 6)
  - Eclipsed: Based on True Events of the Magdalene Laundries (Patricia Burke Brogan), undated (Box 29, Folder 19)